甜蜜日常 但仍有点混乱
♪ It's a sweet life, still a little messy. ♪
奇妙日常 充满了惊喜
♪ Magic life, full of surprises. ♪
迅捷日常
♪ Fast life ♪
凝视我的宝石
♪ Gaze upon my gems! ♪
开心日常 因为我们拥有彼此
♪ It's a fun life because we got each other. ♪
可爱日常
♪ It's a cute life. ♪
以自己的方式生活！
♪ Living life in our own way! ♪
来吧 拿一块蛋糕
♪ Come on, grab a slice of cake. ♪
甜蜜 奇妙 迅捷 时尚 开心 可爱
♪ It's a sweet, magic, fast, posh, fun, cute ♪
小马日常
♪ Pony Life! ♪
每口都是甜蜜的惊喜
♪ A sweet surprise in every bite.  ♪
友谊 彩虹 真的棒
♪ Friendship, rainbows, wuh-oh! ♪
甜蜜
♪ It's a sweet  ♪
奇妙
♪ Magic ♪
迅捷
♪ Fast ♪
时尚
♪ Posh ♪
开心
♪ Fun ♪
可爱
♪ Cut ♪
小马日常
♪ Pony Life! ♪
愿望
最后
这种疯狂必须停止！
This madness has got to stop!
但是 只有许愿魔法
But wish magic is the only thing
强大到足以解除小马镇所有的混乱魔法
Powerful enough to undo all the chaos magic in Ponyville.
但无序拿走了所有的愿望！
But Discord took all the wishes!
等一下
Wait just a sugar-frosted second.
我们探索无序脑袋时
While we were exploring Discord's head,
我得知今天是他的生日
I learned that today is his birthday!
事实上 他从来没有办过生日派对！
In fact, he's never had a birthday party!
这意味着...
Which means...
他才一岁大！
He's one year old!
不对 但我喜欢你的热情
No, but love the enthusiasm.
这意味着 无序会得到一个生日愿望！
It means Discord gets a birthday wish!
就这样！
That's it!
让我们为无序举办一个最棒的生日派对吧！
Let's throw Discord the best birthday party ever!
这样 他会用他的生日愿望
So he'll use his birthday wish,
让小马镇恢复正常！
to return Ponyville back to pony-normal!
耶！但我们必须让它成为一个惊喜
Yes! Buuuut we gotta make it a surprise.
以我对无序的了解
Knowing Discord,
他会像往常一样制造混乱
he'd do his usual chaos thing
毁掉派对和我们最后的希望
and ruin the party and our last hope.
事情多 时间少！
Much to do and little time to do it!
瑞瑞和暮光 你们负责装饰
Rarity and Twilight, you're on decoration duty.
阿杰和小蝶 你们负责音乐
Applejack and Fluttershy, you take care of the music.
我会烤出最酷的生日蛋糕
I'll bake the coolest birthday cake ever,
由我信任的副厨云宝黛茜协助
aided by my trusted sous chef Rainbow Dash.
你好 哈喽！
Hello and hellooooo!
欢迎光临“我们来装饰”
Welcome to Let's Decorate!
我们让每个派对都精彩！
We make every party great!
我们需要一些紧急装饰品
We need some emergency decorations
为了一个惊喜生日派对
for a surprise birthday party.
我爱惊喜！
I love surprises!
别告诉我是为谁准备的！
Don't tell me who it's for!
我想被惊喜到！
I want to be surprised!
是啊···
Yeah...
所以我们需要横幅 气球 彩纸···
So we're gonna need streamers, balloons, confetti...
就把你们最好的东西都给我们吧
Just give us all the best stuff you have.
可我们就有最好的东西！
But we have the best stuff!
让我先看一眼我的储藏室
Let me just peek into my storage room for a moment.
我们什么都没有了
We're completely out of everything.
惊喜！
Surprise!
但你说你什么都有！
But you said you have all the things!
有啊！
We do!
但现在没有
But not right now.
整个店都租出去了 我一定是忘了
The whole store's been rented, and I must've forgotten.
是不是很傻？
Isn't that silly?
最傻了
The silliest.
现在怎么办？我们需要装饰品
What now? We need decorations.
暮光 亲爱的
Twilight, darling,
我可能正好有个解决办法
I might just have a solution.
很抱歉打扰你 DJ Pon-3
Sorry to bother you, DJ Pon-3,
但我们真的需要你的帮助
but we really need your help.
我们要办派对
We're throwin' a party,
想让它超级热闹
and we want to be a real barn-blaster.
你能提供音乐吗？
Will you provide the music?
DJ Pon-3的电报
Telegram for DJ Pon-3.
恭喜
Congrats.
你赢得了为期两周的“阿斑马”热带绿洲度假
You won a two-week vacation to the tropical oasis of Azebra.
它马上开始 旅途愉快
It starts immediately. Happy travels.
真倒霉
Talk about bad luck.
我们现在怎么办？
What do we do now?
呃  DJ Pon-3应该不介意
Uh, DJ Pon-3 doesn't mind
小马租用她的设备 对吧？
when ponies rent her equipment, right?
我有个桶 里面装着些旧道具
I have a bucket full of old props somewhere.
我们可以把它们当装饰用
We can use them as decor.
在这儿！
Here it is!
棒极了
Wonderful.
可以吃吗？
Can we eat it?
它看起来太棒了
It looks incredible.
我得吃了它！
I need to eat it!
还不行
Not yet.
先得涂糖霜
First, we frost.
DJ Pon-3在哪？
Where's DJ Pon-3?
没时间解释了！
No time for a recap!
无序三十分钟后在这儿见我
Discord's meeting me here in thirty minutes,
还有很多事要做！
and there's much to do!
我们来装饰吧！
Let's decorate!
《彭普兰斯的海盗》的道具
Props from The Pirates of Penprance,
《侏罗纪马园》的恐龙装备
dino gear from Jurassic Horse...
还有《独立草》里的外星人！
...and the aliens from Independence Hay!
派对可能还有救！
The party just might be saved!
我的普通糖被换成了
My regular sugar was swapped
我特制的爆炸糖？
with my special stash of exploding sugar?
不———！
Noooooooooooo!
咋了?
What?
嘿 嘿 这是你的生日
Hey, hey, it's your birthday
欢呼 欢呼 又来到这一年
Cheer, cheer for another year
为你的特别日子欢呼！
Hooray for your special day!
多么混乱的景象啊！
What a positively chaotic sight!
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
你们想让我的生日愿望
You want my birthday wish
把小马镇变回正常
to set Ponyville back to normal.
你怎么知道？
How did you know?
我无意中听到了你们的计划
I overheard you ponies planning.
我租了所有东西
I rented everything
从那家烦人又喜庆的小马装饰店
from that annoying cheerful decoration store pony.
是我让DJ甩下你不管的
I got the DJ to leave you in the lurch.
关于交换糖分？
And swapping the sugars？
我好奇那会发生什么
I wonder how that could've happened.
惊喜！
Surprise!
我们早该知道
We should have known
这些疯狂不可能是巧合
this craziness couldn't have been a coincidence.
我就是喜欢混乱！
I just adore chaos!
我想 再见吧 生日愿望
I suppose it's so long, birthday wish,
再见吧 小马镇
and so long, Ponyville.
哦 你大错特错了！腐果卡壳
Oh, how wrong you are, "Frappleclack".
毁掉的派对才是完美的派对！
A ruined party is a perfect party!
今天的混乱就是最棒的生日礼物
Today's chaos has been the perfect birthday present.
我会用我的生日愿望让小马镇恢复正常
I'll use my birthday wish to return Ponyville to normal.
最好快点
Better do it quickly,
因为你的蜡烛快熄灭了！
'cause your candle is almost out!
然后就再见了 愿望
Then it'll be goodbye, wish.
不羁的心
结···结束了？
I-Is it over?
咱···咱能看了吗？
C-Can we look?
我认为它奏效了！
I think it worked!
无序的愿望恢复了秩序！
Discord's wish has restored order!
暮光？穗龙？
Twilight? Spike?
哇哦！“暮光穗龙”！
Whoa! "Twilight Spikle"!
哈哈  真好笑
Ha-ha, very funny.
等等 为什么我是穗龙？
Wait. Why am I Spike?
这太诡异了
This is freaky!
我们的传送门出了点问题
Something's wrong with our portal.
我们被直接吸回来了
We got sucked right back through.
感觉像是我们···
It's like we got...
断开了连接
disconnected.
有点不对劲
Somethin's not right.
嗯  这是肯定的！
Well, that's for sure!
无序的生日愿望本该让一切恢复正常
Discord's birthday wish should've put everything back to normal,
但现在反而比以前更混乱了！
but everything is even more chaotic than before!
抱歉 我得离开一会儿 接个电话
Sorry. Have to split for a moment and take this.
哦 好吧 然后我说···
Oh, okay. And then I said...
也许我们可以再试试——！
Maybe we can try agaaaaain!
好听
Bravo!
我在穗龙的身体里
I'm in Spike's body.
小蝶把每句话都唱出来
Fluttershy is singing everything she says.
萍琪刚才接了个水果电话
Pinkie just answered a piece of fruit.
我认为
I think
宇宙愿望能量和狂野魔法的混合
that the mix of cosmic wish energy and the Wild Side magic
正在扰乱小马利亚的自然秩序！
is messing with the natural order of Equestria!
所以 无序的愿望不够强？
So Discord's wish wasn't strong enough?
恐怕是的
I'm afraid not.
这就意味着 我们两个世界正在融合成一个！
Which means our two worlds are merging into one!
如果那样的话
If that happens,
我们要担心的就不止是一点点混乱了！
we'll have more than a little chaos to worry about!
这看起来不太妙——
This doesn't look goooooood.
冷静点 各位小马
Chill out, everypony.
我想我们能清理掉这些散逸的狂野魔法
I think we can clean up the loose Wild Side magic
并让一切恢复正常
and set everything right.
而且我知道该怎么做
And I know just how to do it.
她很擅长清理 尤其是亮粉
She's very good at cleaning. Especially glitter.
还有 我储藏室里还放着那些奇怪的魔法物品
Also, I still have all those weird magical items in the pantry.
抱歉 妈妈 我待会再打给你
Sorry, mom. Gonna have to call you back.
得去拯救小马利亚了！
Gotta go save Equestria!
好的 计划是什么？
Okay! What's the plan?
首先 我们需要那些物品
First, we'll need those objects
这样我们就能为它们注入我们的魔法
so we can infuse them with our magic.
我们得快点——！
We gotta hurryyyyy!
酷~
Coooool!
让我们来试试它们吧！
Let's test them out!
现在它是一根传送门魔杖了
Now it's a portal wand!
前方的道路充满未知
♪ The road ahead's uncertain ♪
我们该走向何方
♪ Which way will we go ♪
才能收拾这魔法混乱？
♪ To clean up this magic mass? ♪
哦 我们该如何知晓？
♪ Oh, how will we know? ♪
没有简单的指南
♪ There is no simple guide ♪
没有地图指引方向
♪ No map to lead the way ♪
只需倾听你狂野的心
♪ Just listen to your wild heart ♪
听听它在说什么
♪ And what it has to say ♪
上变下或下变上
♪ Downside-up or upside-down ♪
这个世界一片混乱
♪ It's topsy-turvy all around ♪
只需去绽放你的光芒
♪ Just go and shine your light ♪
一切都会好起来
♪ And it'll be all right ♪
上变下或下变上
♪ Downside-up or upside-down ♪
这个小镇一片混乱
♪ It's topsy-turvy in the town ♪
不要放弃战斗
♪ Don't give up the fight ♪
朋友会让一切变好
♪ Friends will make it right ♪
当一切都变得一团糟
♪ When everything goes sideways ♪
我也总能依靠你
♪ I can always count on you ♪
当我的生活变得疯狂
♪ When my life feels wacky ♪
你助我坚持下去
♪ You help me to push through ♪
变化有时让人觉得
♪ Changing can sometimes feel like ♪
世界就要终结
♪ The world is gonna end ♪
但如果你学会顺应它
♪ But if you learn to roll with it ♪
它能成为你朋友
♪ It can be your friend! ♪
DJ Pon-3 来点超赞的节奏
DJ Pon-3, bring that sweet, sweet beat!
狂野之心！心跳不息！
♪ Wild heart! Heart beats! ♪
去完未来又回来
♪ Been to the future and back ♪
见过怪物植物攻击
♪ Seen a monster plant attack ♪
玩过传送门战斗
♪ Played some Portal Combat ♪
甚至遇到一只酷蝙蝠
♪ Even met a cool bat ♪
戳破过巨大气球
♪ Popped a giant balloon ♪
也见过机械小马
♪ Met mechani-ponies, too ♪
弄了个闪亮发型
♪ Got a sparkly updo ♪
遇到点彗星小麻烦
♪ Had a little comet trouble ♪
被困在泡泡里面
♪ Got caught in a bubble ♪
现在我们迷失在废墟
♪ Now we're lost in the rubble ♪
但现在很清楚一点小混乱
♪ But now it's clear to see a little chaos ♪
在和谐中有重要地位
♪ Has a vital place in harmony ♪
没错 狂野是我的一部分
♪ And yeah, wild is a part of me ♪
上变下或下变上
♪ Downside-up or upside-down ♪
这个世界一片混乱
♪ It's topsy-turvy all around ♪
只需去绽放你的光芒
♪ Just go and shine your light ♪
一切都会好起来
♪ And it'll be all right ♪
上变下或下变上
♪ Downside-up or upside-down ♪
这个小镇一片混乱
♪ It's topsy-turvy in this town ♪
不要放弃战斗
♪ Don't give up the fight ♪
朋友会让一切变好
♪ Friends will make it right ♪
不要放弃战斗
♪ Don't give up the fight ♪
不  别放弃战斗
♪ No, don't give up the fight ♪
朋友会让一切变好！
♪ Friends will make it right! ♪
好了 小马们
All right, everypony.
是时候彻底结束这场混乱了！
It's time to end this chaos once and for all!
等等
Wait!
这是不是意味着···
Does this mean...
···永别?
...goodbye?!
我想有可能
I think it might.
但这段时间很开心
But it's been fun.
超级开心
Super fun.
我们还会再见面的
We could meet again.
毕竟 你永远不知道未来会发生什么
After all, you never know what the future holds
嘿！我又变回我了！
Hey! I'm me again!
小马日常
♪ Pony Life ♪
以防这些小马们还需要一点点混乱
Just in case these ponies are in need of a little more chaos.